So, the development of vascular pathways.
First thing, the image we have specifically of the circulatory system,
you have a system that starts from the heart, called the arterial system,
and then you are told it returns to the heart via the
venous system.
I agree it goes out and comes back.
In fact, there are three different venous systems.
One system like this,
a system that is solely related to the, let's say, spinal system.
And thirdly, there is a portal system.
This will drain the entire ectodermic system.
This will drain the entire mesodermic system.
This will drain the entire endodermic system.
You see, indeed, okay, it comes here.
But it can turn back.
It can take other pathways depending on
the pressures and depressions in the body.
You see, suddenly, someone who has an overloaded portal system,
if they cannot return properly, they will take another path,
they will take a caval return system with very specific fields
which are the diaphragmatic exchange zones.
So this means pressures can...
rebalance. So, not only
does it not make a round trip like this,
but it does this
and it can take other
paths. There is like an intelligence
in this system
to go back home
to the heart. It starts well
from the heart, it returns well to the heart,
but in your venous system,
the circulatory system,
the view we have of it, dates back to the 17th
century. This means that now,
it has been updated, the first
to study this were Mr. Herlihy and Mr. Batson, and it's not the same return. My
reaction was yes but I was told that in the veins there were valves that
prevented backward flow. Well, in fact, it's just in the large veins but not at all in
the entire
network. There are very few small valves like that. Because we will study the
cardinal veins which will become subcardinal and supracardinal.
You have another system
called the vitelline system related to the liver. And then a third level,
will be
the entire umbilical system, it will be the entire development of the venous system
that we
will reevaluate in the caval-portal spinal system and that we will reintegrate into
osteopathic practice. The entire cardinal system will change so much
that we will see
it in detail to form tissues, structures that will integrate both
in the structures and that are unfurled.
and mesodermic. I found a method where you can put this into practice,
where I summarize
it all eventually. But you need to understand the meaning. The stasis, the changes
in abdominal pressure,
etc. Like someone coming in with lower back pain, it can be an overload of the portal system.
And so it is necessary to clear the spinal system due to portal overload.
And that is where you have
Everything that is stasis will cause local acidity, you see, that will need
to be cleared.
We notice that it will always follow the same pattern,
that when I have a tumor in my sacrum, I almost always have, at the metastatic level,
the left kidney, left lung, and brain.
But we find that there is always the same line.
This means that in prostate issues, it can be found here.
Moreover, there is a continuity.
vascular continuity between the vertebral sinuses and the sacral sinuses of the small
pelvis.
A blood test done in one arm here does not account for the entirety of a blood test
that would be taken from a venous, arterial system or other.